A Finding Aid to the Henry Varnum Poor Papers, 1873-2001, bulk 1904-1970, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1873-1985; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  - E, 1952-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Eyerly, Jeannie
  - F, 1941-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Fanning, Maggie
    Federal Works Agency, Public Buildings Administration
    Federal Seaboard Terra Cotta Corporation
    Fieldhouse, Murray
    Flack, Frank
    Fraser, James
    Friant, Jim
  - G, 1919-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Galerie Morency
    Garnett, David
    Garrett, Alice
    Gerard, Constance
    Giacomini, L.
    Greeft, Adele
    Green, Sam
  - H, 1943-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Hamlin, Jane
    Hayman, D.
    Heliker, John
    Henson, William
    Hilton, Elizabeth
    Hoffman, Letha
    Holabird, Dorothy
    Hooper, M.
    Houseman
    Howarth, Pauline
    Howell, J.F.
    Humenho, Alexander
  - H, 1955-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Hougland, Josephine Poor
  - J, 1943-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Jensen, Richard
    Jones, Joseph
    Johnson, Edward
  - K, 1945-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Kansas State College
    Kansas State University
    Kappo
    Kelly, Jack
    Kienbusch, William
    Koffler, Bob
  - L, 1910; 1946-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Leach, Bernard
    Lentz, Harris
    Levenstein, Harper
    London New Art School
    Lorson, Mrs. Clem
  - M, 1938-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Mager, N.H.
    Mangravite, Peppino
    Markham, Kyra
    Marston, M.R.
    McKenzie, Richard
    Mikkelson Family
    Mitchell, C.L.
    Mitrotti, Leslie
    Moore, Mary McClure
    Muller, Ray
    Mumford, Lewis
  - N, 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
    National Academy of Design
    National Institute of Arts and Letters
    New York University
    New World Foundation
  - O, 1942-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Office of Emergency Management
    O'Neil, J.F.
  - P, 1911-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts
    Pennsylvania Bar Association
    Peterson, Alberta
    Phillips, Miriam
    Pomerance, Ralph
    Poor, Henry
    Poor, Herbert
    Poor, Val
    Poor
    Postrung, R.
  - R, 1944-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Ramsbusch, Viggo
    Reed, Bob
    Reeves, Ruth
    Reynolds Enterprises
    Riddens, Shaskins
    Rockland Light and Power Company
    Rossin, Alfred
    Ryan, Lila
  - S, 1918-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Sain, Lydia
    Salina Art Association
    Saltonstall and Morton
    San Francisco Art Association
    Sanchez, Tony
    Sands, Mrs. Edward
    Scheftel, Geraldine
    Scherfee, Samuel
    Shapero, Mrs. Harold
    Short, Marie
    Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture
    Spina, Paul
    Springfield High School Art Association
    Sloper, Ann
    Smith, Claude
    Smith, David
    Smithsonian Institution
    Soyer, Raphael
    Steinbeck, John
    Stevens, Marti
    Stillman
    Stone, Eva and Herbert
    Stone, Vivian and Charles
    Strong, F.S.
    Sullivan, George
    Swain, Allen
    Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts
    Syracuse University
  - T, 1943-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Taylor, Tom
    Teller Commercial Company
    Terwilliger, Nellie and Fred
    Toomer, Marjorie Content
  - V, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Vihlein, Jane
  - W, 1924-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Walker, Maynard
    War Department
    Watkins, Franklin
    Watson, Forbes
    Watson, Nan
    Webb, Mrs. Vanderbilt (Aileen)
    Weeks, Lynn and Jim
    Wigglesworth, Anne Parker
    Williams, Gil
    Wilson, Betty Balliett
    Wolslagel, Earl
    Women's Garment Manufacturers Supply Association
    Wyche, Mrs. Cyril H.
  - Y, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Yelin, Saul
  - Z, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Zorach, Marguerite
  - First Names Only, 1944-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Outgoing Drafts, 1918-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Marion Dorn, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Condolence Letters, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Business Correspondence, 1941; 1971-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
    Includes correspondence regarding estate matters, Henry Varnum Poor exhibitions, and loans
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1904-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1916-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1920-1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1924-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1932-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, 1938-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Henry Varnum Poor to Family, circa 1900-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1882-1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1906-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1914-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1922-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1940-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, 1952-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Poor Relatives and Friends, circa 1900-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Graham Family Letters, 1965; 1873-1889; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Includes many photocopies
  - Empty Envelopes, Archival Resource Key
    - To Mr. and Mrs. A. J. Poor, 1910-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - To Mr. and Mrs. A. J. Poor, 1930-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - To Eva and Herbert Stone, 1931-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Writings and Notes, circa 1944-1974; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Writings by Henry Varnum Poor include manuscripts of his two published books, An Artist Sees Alaska and A Book of Pottery: From Mud to Immortality. There are four notebooks containing information about pottery, tile procedures, and glazes, etc., film scripts, two journals, notes, including those from his studies in London and Paris, lists, speeches, and drafts of articles including "Painting is Being Talked to Death," published in the first issue of Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions, April 1953.
  Among the writings by others are poems, notes, and reminiscences, including those by M. R. ("Muktuk") Marston, Waldo Peirce, Bessie Brueuer Poor, Josephine Poor, and unidentified individuals. The unsigned "Outline for a Proposed Artists Corps," circa 1942, is most likely written by Olin Dows or George Biddle.
  Additional scattered writings and notes are found in biographical materials (Series 1) and within Poor's sketchbooks (Series 5).
  - By Henry Varnum Poor, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Articles, Archival Resource Key
      - "Painting is Being Talked to Death" and item for "Notes on Art Education" (both published in Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions), 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - "The Relation of Art to Life", circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Books, An Artist Sees Alaska (manuscript), Archival Resource Key
      - Table of Contents and Introduction, circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - "Penn Station", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - "San Francisco", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - "Seattle", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - "The Turner Passage", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - "Fort Richardson", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - "Days from My Diary at Ladd Field", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - "Two Days on the Yukon", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - "Nome", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "Golovin", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Unalakleet", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - "Nome Again", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - "Bering Strait", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - "Teller", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - "Cape Prince of Wales", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - "Little Diomede", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - "Shishmareff", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - "Kotzebuu - Seat of Empire", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - "Kotzebue", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - "Point Hope", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - "The Arctic Ocean", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - "Wainwright", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - "Point Barrow", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - "Journey Back", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Books, A Book of Pottery: From Mud to Immortality, Archival Resource Key
      - Outlines, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Longhand Draft of Chapters 2-11, and Fragments, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
      - Typescript Draft of Chapters 1-11, and Fragments, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Film Script, "Painting in True Fresco", circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fragments, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Journals, Archival Resource Key
    - March 9-June 11, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - May 27-Sept. 20, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Photocopy
  - Lists, Miscellaneous, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks, 1921-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Notebooks may include notes on pottery, tile procedures, glazes, measurements, and lists of supplies or various projects.
  - Notes, Archival Resource Key
    - "Drawing Ideas from Slade School and Walter Sickert in London," "The Whistler Palette and Notes Gathered from [Clifford] Addams," "Grafton Galleries Post-Impressionists," and Untitled Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1910-1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Painting Points to Remember from Henry Varnum Poor", 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Mimeographed sheet
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Report, "Virgin Island Clays", circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Speeches, "Remarks on the Frescoes in Old Main at the Pennsylvania State College" and "Painting, Sculpture, and People", 1964[?]; 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - By Other Authors, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
    - Marston, M. R. ("Muktuk"), circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Account of Henry Varnum Poor rescuing an eskimo
    - Peirce, Waldo, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
      "A Tribute to My Mother-in-Law"
    - Poor, Bessie Breuer, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Poor, Josephine, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Poem, photocopy
    - Unidentified (probably Olin Dows or George Biddle), circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
      "Outline for a Proposed Artists Corps"
    - Unidentified, Archival Resource Key
      - "The Dolphin Passed Last Night: A Mural Drama", circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Notes on "Rakku" and "Painting w/ Ethyl Sillicate", circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Poem, "The New Moon of our Incoherence", circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Subject Files, 1928-1975; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 3, OV 23
  Subject files are found on various topics and appear to have been established by Poor. The largest group is for the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture and includes financial reports, by-laws, correspondence, miscellaneous administrative files, and minutes. Contents of the files are varied and may contain correspondence, printed material, and photographs.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Advisory Committee on Art, Division of Cultural Cooperation, Department of State, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - American Designers' Gallery, Inc., 1928-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Oversized material housed in OV 23
  - Automobile, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Benton, William, 1966-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - A Book of Pottery: From Mud to Immortality (Prentice-Hall), 1954-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Dickson, Harold (Pennsylvania State College), 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Insurance, 1937-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Marston, M. R. ("Muktuk"), 1943-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Pennsylvania State College, The Land Grant Frescoes, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions, Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Reality, Nos. 1-3, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Articles, Editorials, Letters to the Editor Published in Other Periodicals, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Sales, Archival Resource Key
    - Auctions and Miscellaneous Galleries, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Frank K. M. Rehn, Inc., 1943-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Sales and Consignments, Market Fair, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Archival Resource Key
    - Budgets and Financial Reports, 1960-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - By-Laws, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence of Anne Poor, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence of Henry Varnum Poor, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Grant Proposal, Old Dominion Foundation, circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Leases, 1955-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Master Plans, 1966-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Minutes of Board of Governors, 1961-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Minutes of Board of Trustees, 1963-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Minutes of Faculty Meetings, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Minutes of Officers' Meetings, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Notes and Lists, circa 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Poor Scholarship Fund, 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Printed Material, 1946-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Reports and Recommendations, 1951-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Scholarships, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Sixteen Year Survey and Evaluation, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Taxes, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Truro, Massachusetts Property, 1952-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Utilities, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - War Posters, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Oversized American Designers' Gallery Blueprints and Floor Plans scanned with Box 3, Folder 26, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 23)
- Artwork, circa 1890s-circa 1961; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-6, 9-10, OV 19-22
  Artwork by Henry Varnum Poor consists of loose drawings, sketches, designs, watercolors, and prints, as well as 45 sketchbooks. Many are studies for paintings, murals, and pottery. Included is work done in France, 1918-1919, and produced in Alaska while a war correspondent in 1943. Also found are commissioned illustrations and illustrations drawn for his monograph A Book of Pottery: From Mud to Immortality. Other artists represented are Anne Poor and Ernest Watson.
  Additional drawings and prints are found in architectural projects (Series 6).
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  5.1: By Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1890s-circa 1961
  5.2: By Other Artists, circa 1938-circa 1949
  - By Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1890s-circa 1961; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    Some of the unidentified figure studies, portraits, and heads of women are probably Bessie and Anne Poor. Illustrations include those produced for Ethan Frome and The Scarlet Letter, and some that may have been intended for A Book of Pottery. Drawings produced in 1943 while Poor was a war correspondent in Alaska may have served as visual notes or illustrations for An Artist Sees Alaska. Also found are a small number of watercolors and prints. Most prints show the aftermath of World War I in France, and a Christmas card sent by Henry Varnum and Marion Dorn Poor features a print.
    A fair number of drawings and sketches are on sheets of paper with images on both sides; often, they are very different subjects. Since item level description with cross referencing is not provided, researchers conducting exhaustive studies of specific categories or subjects of Poor's works on paper are advised to examine all.
    Loose drawings and sketches are arranged by subject.
    - Animals, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 1
    - Birds and Fish, circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 2
    - Designs, Archival Resource Key
      - Bathroom Fixtures and Tiles, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 3
      - Ceiling Tiles, Union Dime Savings Bank, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Tiles, Phillip Goodwin Pool Shelter, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 4
      - Covers of Skowhegan School Publications, circa 1946-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Exhibition Announcement, Montross Gallery, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Fireplaces, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Furniture, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 3 and OV 19
    - Figures, circa 1890s-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12-17)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 5
    - Figures, Nude, circa 1920-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18-21)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 6
    - Figure Studies (hands and feet), circa 1920-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Illustrations, Archival Resource Key
      - A Book of Pottery by Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23-26)
        Oversized material in Box 10, Folders 8-9
      - Miscellaneous Illustrations of Pottery Construction Techniques (possibly for A Book of Pottery, by Henry Varnum Poor), circa 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Ethan Frome, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - The Scarlet Letter, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Landscapes, 1918-1919; 1939; 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30-37)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 9, Folders 7-9 and OV 20
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1918-1919; 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
      Oversized material housed in Box 9, Folder 10
    - Mural Studies, Archival Resource Key
      - "Ben Hecht Leda and Swan", circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
        Oversized material housed in OV 21
      - Unidentified, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Plants, circa 1910-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 1
    - Portraits and Heads (unidentified), Archival Resource Key
      - Children, undated; 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
        Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 2
      - Men, undated; 1918-1919; 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
        Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folders 3-4
      - Women, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7-10)
        Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 5
    - Portraits (identified), circa 1930-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Includes Bessie Breuer, Charles Duback, Jim Fickes, David Friedenthal, Stuard Frost, Ben Hecht, Helen Hayes, DeWitt Peters, Rollo Peters, Alfred Poor, Herbert Poor, Peter Poor, Ed Rowan, Concetta Scaravaglione, and John and Gwen Steinbeck Family. Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 6.
    - Portraits (self-portraits), circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 7
    - Pottery, Archival Resource Key
      - Plates, circa 1920-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Vessels and Birdhouses, circa 1920-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Still Life, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 10
    - Prints, 1918-1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 11 and OV 22
    - Sketchbooks, Archival Resource Key
      - Sketchbooks 1 and 2, 1918-circa 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
        France
      - Sketchbooks 3 and 4, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
        Early pottery drawings and notes